[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Professor Razzak was a scholar ____ repute.(Fill in the gap)",
    "options": ["In", "of", "after", "by"],
    "answer": "of"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "'David Coperfield' is a/an ___ novel.",
    "options": ["Victorian", "Elizabethan", "Romantic", "Modern"],
    "answer": "Victorian"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "‘Elegy written in a country churchyard’ is written by-",
    "options": [
      "William Wordsworth",
      "Thomas Gray",
      "John Keats",
      "W.B. Yeats"
    ],
    "answer": "Thomas Gray"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "John Smith is good ___ Mathematics. (Fill in the gap)",
    "options": ["of", "in", "at", "after"],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Shakespeare's Measure for Measure is a successful---",
    "options": ["comedy", "tragedy", "tragi-comedy", "melo drama"],
    "answer": "comedy"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Teacher said, “The earth __ round the sun.”",
    "options": ["moved", "has moved", "will be moving", "moves"],
    "answer": "moves"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The romantic age in English literature began with the publication of ___.",
    "options": [
      "Preface to Shakespeare",
      "Preface to Ancient Mariners",
      "Preface to Dr. Johnson",
      "Preface to Lyrical Ballads"
    ],
    "answer": "Preface to Lyrical Ballads"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "In English grammar ______, deals with formation of sentences.",
    "options": ["Morphology", "Etymology", "Syntax", "Semantics"],
    "answer": "Syntax"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which of the followings books is written by Thomas Hardy?",
    "options": [
      "Vanity Fair",
      "Pride and Prejudice",
      "The Return of the Native",
      "Oliver Twist"
    ],
    "answer": "The Return of the Native"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "He insisted __ there. (Fill in the gap)",
    "options": ["is to go", "on my going", "over going", "to go"],
    "answer": "on my going"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "The idiom ‘A-stitch is times saves nine’ - refers to the importance of-",
    "options": [
      "saving lives",
      "timely action",
      "saving time",
      "time tailoring"
    ],
    "answer": "timely action"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "\"\"\"Frailty thy name is woman\"\"___ is a famous dialogue from.\"",
    "options": [
      "W. Shakespeare",
      "Christopher Marlow",
      "Johns Webstan",
      "T.S. Eliot"
    ],
    "answer": "W. Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "The poem ‘The Solitary Reaper’ is written by-",
    "options": ["W.B. Yeats", "W.H. Auden", "W. Wordsworth", "Ezra Pound"],
    "answer": "W. Wordsworth"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "‘The Merchant of Venice’ is a Shakespearean play about",
    "options": ["a Moor", "a Roman", "a Turk", "a Jew"],
    "answer": "a Jew"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "What would be the right antonym for ‘initiative’?",
    "options": ["indolence", "Apathy", "enterprise", "activity"],
    "answer": "Apathy"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "The play ‘Candida’ is by-",
    "options": ["G. B. Shaw", "Shakespeare", "Arthur Miller", "James Joyce"],
    "answer": "G. B. Shaw"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "Which of the following writers belongs to the romantic period in English literature?",
    "options": [
      "A. Tennyson",
      "Alexander Pope",
      "John Dryden",
      "S.T. Coleridge"
    ],
    "answer": "S.T. Coleridge"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "This could have worked if I ___ been more cautious",
    "options": ["might", "have", "had", "would"],
    "answer": "had"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "The Climax of a plot is what happens-",
    "options": [
      "at the height",
      "in the beginning",
      "at the end",
      "in the confrontation"
    ],
    "answer": "at the height"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "London town is found a living being in the works of-",
    "options": [
      "Charles Dickens",
      "Thomas Hardy",
      "W. Congreve",
      "D. H. Lawrence"
    ],
    "answer": "Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "I have been living in Dhaka ____ 2000.",
    "options": ["till", "after", "from", "since"],
    "answer": "since"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "\"Give the antonym of the word \"\"transitory”-\"",
    "options": ["temporary", "permanent", "transparent", "short-lived"],
    "answer": "permanent"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Verb of “Number” is-",
    "options": ["number", "numbering", "enumerate", "numerical"],
    "answer": "enumerate"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "'Child is the father of man' is taken from the poem of—",
    "options": [
      "W. Wordsworth",
      "S.T. Coleridge",
      "P.B. Shelley",
      "A.C. Swinburne"
    ],
    "answer": "W. Wordsworth"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Slow and steady ___ the race. (Fill in the gap)",
    "options": ["has won", "win", "wins", "won"],
    "answer": "wins"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "“Man is a political animal” - who said this?",
    "options": ["Dante", "Socrates", "Plato", "Aristotle"],
    "answer": "Aristotle"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Who is known as “the poet of nature” in English literature?",
    "options": [
      "John Milton",
      "Williams Words Worth",
      "Lord Tennyson",
      "John Keats"
    ],
    "answer": "Williams Words Worth"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Identify the correct sentence?",
    "options": [
      "Yesterday, he has gone home",
      "Yesterday, he did gone home",
      "Yesterday, he went home",
      "Yesterday, he had gone home"
    ],
    "answer": "Yesterday, he went home"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "\"\"\"A Passage to India” is written by-\"",
    "options": [
      "E.M. Forster",
      "Rudyard Kipling",
      "Galls Worthy",
      "A. H. Auden"
    ],
    "answer": "E.M. Forster"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "\"\"\"Gitanjali\"\" of Rabindranath Tagore was translated by-\"",
    "options": ["Robert Frost", "W.B. Yeats", "John Keats", "Rudyard Kipling"],
    "answer": "W.B. Yeats"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "“Venerate” Means–",
    "options": ["abuse", "respect", "defame", "accuse"],
    "answer": "respect"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Credit tk 5000 ___ my account.",
    "options": ["in", "with", "against", "to"],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "‘To do away with’ means-",
    "options": ["to get rid of", "to repeat", "to start", "to drive off"],
    "answer": "to get rid of"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Who of the following writers was not a novelist?",
    "options": ["Charles Dickens", "W.B. Yeats", "James Joyce", "Jane Austen"],
    "answer": "W.B. Yeats"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Which one is a correct sentence?",
    "options": [
      "paper is made by wood",
      "paper is made of wood",
      "paper is made from wood",
      "paper is made on wood"
    ],
    "answer": "paper is made from wood"
  }
]
